

Ilia Nikolaenko

Senior iOS Developer

Eight years' experience in iOS Development, as well as the experience of organizing the development process. Experience in game development, client-server applications, applications for companies and governments.

💌 nikolaenkoim@gmail.com 📘 +49 152 24061866 🛾 🦞 Munich

TOP PROJECTS IN APPSTORE

- One of the most popular puzzle games in the store Magic Jigsaw Puzzles: https://apps.apple.com/app/id439873467
- Secure application for corporate clients with huge functionality SecurePIM: https://apps.apple.com/app/id929060545
- Client application for the most advanced mobile operator in Russia YOTA: https://apps.apple.com/app/id871741640 π

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior iOS Developer

Jun 2017 - Present

Virtual Solution AG (ww.virtual-solution.com), Germany, Berlin-Munich

Key Responsibilities

- Working in the large command on large application SecurePIM (https://goo.gl/1GwWpa).
- Ensuring security and stability in the development of SecurePIM application
- Contributing to the contacts module (synchronization, interface, new features) of the SecurePIM application

Technology

Objective-C, UIKit, CoreData, AFNetworking, ActiveSync, CocoaPods, Unit Tests, OCMock, JIRA, Bitbucket (Code Review), Jenkins, CI, GIT-Flow, SCRUM

Head of Mobile Development Department

Mar 2016 - May 2017

Digital Zone (www.dz.ru), Russia, Ulyanovsk

Key Responsibilities

- Engaged in building a mobile department from scratch
- Directly involved in the development of projects for iOS
- Developed and modified three applications for internal use within government corporations and one for the mobile operator (https://goo.gl/v9mHXS).

Technology

Objective-C, Swift, UIKit, CoreAnimation, CoreData, AFNetworking, REST API, VIPER, Reactive programming (ReactiveCocoa), Dependency injection (Typhoon), CocoaPods, GIT, Redmine, SCRUM

Senior iOS Developer

Feb 2012 - Feb 2016

XIMAD (now ZIMAD) (www.zimad.com), Russia, Ulyanovsk

Key Responsibilities

- Started as the only iOS developer in the Ulyanovsk office
- Gathered the team together with which we worked on the iOS game Magic Jigsaw Puzzles (https://goo.gl/4w8ARy).

Technology

Objective-C, UIKit, CoreAnimation, CoreData, Cocos-2D, OpenGL, AFNetwork, custom API, JIRA, SVN, GIT, SCRUM

Current Project

"This or That" (https://goo.gl/do8ifY)

In this game you will be asked questions with two possible answers. After answering, you can see how the other players responded. You can also add your own questions. In the second version there were comments.

Technology

version 1: Objective-C, CocoaPods, Core Data, RESTful, AFNetworking, CoreAnimation version 2: Swift, Carthage, RESTful, Alamofire, RxSwift, CoreAnimation (release planned for March 2019)

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

Coursera:

Algorithmic Toolbox - https://goo.gl/JKbyne
Data Structures - https://goo.gl/F9P9i4
Algorithms on Graphs - https://goo.gl/yrC1jc
Algorithms on String - https://goo.gl/FEG7yZ

Swift - https://goo.gl/s4AvDV

EDUCATION

Specialist Degree in Organization Management

Ulyanovsk State University – Russia 2009 – 2012

Specialist Degree in Applied Informatics

Ulyanovsk State University – Russia 2007 – 2012